informatica.com 2019-08-31

# Informatica Privacy Policy | Informatica

**Last Updated** : August 12, 2019

This Privacy Policy explains how Informatica LLC, Informatica Ireland EMEA UC and their respective subsidiaries (“Informatica”) collect, use and share your information. This Privacy Policy applies to information we collect when you use our websites, mobile applications and other online products and services (collectively, the “Services”) or when you otherwise interact with us, including when you attend events hosted or attended by Informatica, contact us for customer support or visit our premises, facilities or offices (collectively, our “facilities”). Please note that third parties host the e-commerce platforms of our Services that accept payment cards: Digital River, Inc. (Informatica Marketplace), Zuora, Inc. (Informatica Cloud Express), and Cornerstone OnDemand, Inc. (Informatica Education Services). As a result, any information you provide in connection with a purchase made via the Services will be collected by these third parties and governed by the third parties’ separate privacy policies. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the information processed by Informatica about its employees or job applicants, which is governed by a separate personnel privacy notice. It also does not apply to information processed by Informatica on behalf of its customers via the Services, as further described in Informatica’s data processing agreement available on the Informatica Legal Information Website at <https://www.informatica.com/content/dam/informatica-com/en/docs/legal/online-data-processing-agreement.pdf>.

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the date at the top of the policy and, in some cases, we may provide you with additional notice (such as by adding a statement to our website homepages or sending you an email notification) or otherwise seek additional consent in accordance with applicable law. We encourage you to review the Privacy Policy whenever you access the Services to stay informed about our information practices and the ways you can help protect your privacy.

_Collection of Information_

_Information You Provide to Us_

We collect information you provide directly to us. For example, we collect information when you create an account (including a product user account), participate in any interactive features of the Services, fill out a form, participate in a contest, promotion or survey, register for an event or course, make a purchase, request customer support or otherwise communicate with us. The types of information you may choose to provide include your name, email address, postal address, phone number, fax number, payment information, gender, and information about your company and current position.

_Information We Collect Automatically When You Use the Services_

When you access or use our Services, we automatically collect some or all of the following information about you:

  * Log Information: We log information about your use of the Services, including the type of browser you use, access times, pages viewed, your IP address and the page you visited before navigating to our Services.
  * Device Information: We collect information about the computer or mobile device you use to access our Services, including the hardware model, operating system and version, unique device identifiers and mobile network information.
  * Location Information: We collect information about the precise location of your device each time you access or use one of our mobile applications. We collect this information in accordance with the permission process established by your mobile device operating system. If you want to later opt out of this collection, please see “Your Choices” below.
  * Product Usage Information: When you use our enterprise products and services on behalf of your organization, we collect information about your device and your use of those products and services, including the device IP address, login credentials, time zone, error messages, product interactions and configurations and other similar usage information.
  * Information Collected by Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies: We use various technologies to collect information, and this includes sending cookies to your computer or mobile device. For more information about cookies, and how to disable them, please see our Cookie Policy at <https://www.informatica.com/legal/cookie-policy.html>.

_Information We Collect From Other Sources_

We also obtain information from other sources and combine that with information we collect through our Services. For example, if you connect an Informatica account with your social media account, we may have access to certain information from the company that owns or operates the social media account in accordance with the authorization procedures determined by such social media company. Informatica also receives information about the company you may work for and your approximate location from data enrichment service providers. Additionally, Informatica receives information about you from other third parties whom you have authorized to share your information, or who collect information in connection with co-branded offerings.

_Information We Collect at Our Facilities_

If you visit our facilities, the video security cameras we use to help protect our employees, visitors, and property may record digital images of you, and we may collect information from you to enable us to identify you for security purposes.

_Use of Information_

We use information about you for the following purposes:

  * Provide, maintain and improve our Services;
  * Provide and deliver the products and services you request, process transactions and send you related information, including confirmations and invoices;
  * Send you technical notices, updates, security alerts and support and administrative messages;
  * Respond to your comments, questions and requests and provide customer service;
  * Communicate with you about products, services, offers, promotions, rewards, and events offered by Informatica and others, and provide news and information we think will be of interest to you;
  * Monitor and analyze trends, usage and activities in connection with our Services;
  * Personalize and improve the Services and provide advertisements, content or features that match user profiles or interests;
  * Help prevent unauthorized access to our facilities, secure property and information, protect the health and safety of our personnel and visitors, and detect and prevent criminal behavior or misconduct;
  * Comply with our legal obligations; and
  * Process and deliver contest entries and rewards.

_Sharing of Information_

We share information about you as follows or as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy:

  * In connection with a joint marketing campaign, seminar, Informatica Marketplace product offering or other product or service offered by Informatica in conjunction with a third party, we share your information with the third parties participating in such offering and such parties may use this information for their direct marketing purposes. Please see “Your Rights to Information about Sharing” below for more information about this sharing.
  * With resellers of Informatica products and services or with sellers of products and services complementary to Informatica products and services, in order to pursue sales opportunities and for other direct marketing purposes. Please see “Your Rights to Information about Sharing” below for more information about this sharing.
  * With vendors, consultants and other service providers who need access to such information to perform services for us, including
    * providing Product Usage Information to analytics service providers to help Informatica understand how users use our Services, including Google Analytics, which processes data as described at <https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites>;
    * data enrichment service providers that may use the data we provide to help provide similar services to other customers;
  * In response to a request for information if we are required by, or believe disclosure is required by, any applicable law, regulation or legal process, including in connection with lawful requests by law enforcement, national security, or other public authorities;
  * To protect the rights, property and safety of Informatica or others;
  * If you use our Services on behalf of one of our enterprise customers, we share certain information about you and your use of our Services with that customer;
  * In connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, financing or acquisition of all or a portion of our business to another company; and
  * With your consent or at your direction, including if we notify you through our Services that the information you provide will be shared in a particular manner and you provide such information.

We also share aggregated or de-identified information, which cannot reasonably be used to identify you.

_Social Sharing Features_

The Services offer social sharing features and other integrated tools (such as the Facebook “Like” button), which let you share actions you take on our Services with other media and vice versa. The use of such features enables the sharing of information with your friends or the public, depending on the settings you establish with the entity that provides the social sharing feature. For more information about the purpose and scope of data collection and processing in connection with social sharing features, please visit the privacy policies of the entities that provide these features.

_Advertising and Analytics Services Provided by Others_

We allow others to serve advertisements on our behalf across the Internet and to provide analytics services on our behalf. These entities use cookies, web beacons and other technologies to collect information about your use of the Services and other websites, including your IP address, web browser, pages viewed, time spent on pages, links clicked and conversion information. This information is used by Informatica and these entities to analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, deliver advertising and content targeted to your interests on our Services and other websites, and better understand your online activity. This Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we are not responsible for, third-party cookies, web beacons, or other tracking technologies. For more information about cookies, including how you may be able to opt out of interest-based ads, please see our Cookie Policy at <https://www.informatica.com/legal/cookie-policy.html>.

_Transfer of Information_

Informatica processes information in the United States and other countries. Accordingly, we and our service providers may transfer your information to, or store or access it in, jurisdictions that may not provide equivalent levels of data protection as your home jurisdiction. We will take steps to ensure that your personal data receives an adequate level of protection in the jurisdictions in which we process it. For instance, data transferred from the European Economic Area (“EEA”) to Informatica LLC and its subsidiaries in the United States will be processed pursuant to the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield (see below for more details). In other cases, we will use European Commission-approved Standard Contractual Clauses to ensure an adequate level of protection for data originating from the EEA. Copies of the Standard Contractual Clauses we use to facilitate the transfer of data outside the EEA are available [here](http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=CELEX%3A32004D0915) and [here](http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/TXT/?uri=CELEX%3A32010D0087).

_Individuals in the European Economic Area_

If we collect your personal data while you are located in the EEA, you have certain rights and protections under the law regarding the processing of this personal data. Please see the sections below for more details.

_Controllers.  _

Informatica Ireland EMEA UC and Informatica LLC are co-controllers of the personal data collected about you.

_Legal Basis for Processing_

When we process this personal data we will only do so in the following situations:

  * We need to use your personal data to perform our responsibilities under our contract with you (e.g., processing payments for and providing our services you have requested).
  * We have a legitimate interest in processing your personal data. For example, we process the personal data we collect from you to send you marketing communications, to communicate with you about changes to our Services, to enhance the safety and security of our facilities, and to provide, secure, and improve our Services.
  * If we request your consent to a specific processing activity, and you provide your consent in the manner indicated.
  * In some cases, processing will be necessary for compliance with a legal obligation, such as response to legal process requests.

_Data Retention_

We store this personal data for as long as is necessary for the purposes for which we originally collected it. We may retain certain information for legitimate business purposes or as required by law.

_Data Subject Requests_

If you are in the EEA, you have the right to access personal data we hold about you and to ask that your personal data be corrected. In certain cases, you may also have the right to request that we erase data we are processing or to restrict or object to certain of our processing activities. You may also have the right to request that we provide the personal data you have provided us in a portable form for transmission to another controller’s service. If you would like to exercise any of these rights, you may contact us as indicated in the “Contact Us” section below.

_Questions or Complaints_

If you are in the EEA and have a concern about our processing of personal data that we are not able to resolve, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the data protection authority where you reside. For contact details of your local Data Protection Authority, please see: <https://edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/board/members_en>.

_EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework_

Informatica LLC and its US subsidiaries adhere in their processing of personal data received from the EEA (“EU Data”) to the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework Principles established by the U.S. Department of Commerce and the European Commission (the “Principles”). For more information about the Principles, please visit the Department of Commerce’s [Privacy Shield website](https://www.privacyshield.gov/). 

Please direct any inquiries or complaints regarding our compliance with the Principles to the point of contact listed in the “Contact Us” section below. If Informatica does not resolve your complaint, you may submit your complaint free of charge for resolution to JAMS, Informatica’s designated independent Privacy Shield dispute resolution provider, at <https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield>. Under certain conditions specified by the Principles, you may also be able to invoke binding arbitration to resolve your complaint. Informatica is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission. If Informatica shares EU Data with a third-party service provider that processes the data solely on Informatica’s behalf, then Informatica may be held liable for that third party’s processing of EU Data in violation of the Principles, unless Informatica can prove that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

_Security_

Informatica takes reasonable measures to help protect information about you from loss, theft, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.

_Your Choices_

_Access Rights_

If you are a resident of a country that provides you with the right to request a copy of the personal data Informatica holds about you and/or to correct any inaccuracies within such data, and Informatica is required by applicable laws to respond to such requests, then you may address such requests to the contact information provided in the “Contact Us” section below. Informatica will use reasonable efforts to supply, correct or delete information that we hold about you or to advise you if we are not required by applicable laws to comply with such requests.

_Account Information_

If you have registered for an account via our Services, you may update, correct or delete your account information by logging into your online account.

_Location Information_

Some of our mobile applications collect precise geolocation information from your mobile device. Prior to collecting such information, you will be asked to consent to the application’s collection of this information. If you initially consent to our collection of location information, you may be able to subsequently stop the collection of this information through your device operating system settings. You may also stop our collection of location information by following the standard uninstall process to remove our mobile applications from your device.

_Promotional Communications_

You may opt out of receiving promotional communications from Informatica by following the instructions provided in those communications or by managing your email preferences at <https://now.informatica.com/UnsubscribePage.html>.  Please note that if you opt out of receiving promotional communications, we may still send you transactional or relationship messages, such as those about your account or our ongoing business relations.

_Your Rights to Information about Sharing_

Residents of California and residents of certain international countries may request certain details, pursuant to applicable laws, about how their information is shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes. If you are a resident of one of these jurisdictions, and would like to make such a request, please contact us at [privacy@informatica.com](mailto:privacy@informatica.com). 

_Contact Us_

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, requests in regard to your personal data or complaints, please contact us at:

Informatica LLC  
Attn: Chief Privacy Officer  
2100 Seaport Blvd  
Redwood City, CA 94063 U.S.A.  
Fax: 650-385-5500  

Or, if you are a resident of the EEA:

Informatica Ireland EMEA UC  
(Fifth Floor)  
1 Windmill Lane  
SOBO District  
Dublin 2, Ireland
